Finding Aid for John Richard Behee Sound Recordings, 1969-1974
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John Richard Behee sound recordings 1969-1974
Behee, John Richard.
29 cassette sound recordings and 1 folder
95100 Aa 2
Historian of University of Michigan athletics, most notably football. Sound cassettes of interviews with African American athletes regarding their experiences at the University of Michigan.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of John Behee (donor no. 4889 ).
The collection is open to research.
John Behee received his doctorate at the University of Michigan. He is the author of two books on University of Michigan athletic history.
The collection consists of audio cassettes of interviews with African American athletes regarding their experiences at the University of Michigan. Included is the proposal Behee wrote for the oral history project. The interivews were part of the Behee's research for his book Hail to the Victors.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Behee, John Richard.; African American athletes--Michigan.; Discrimination in sports.; University of Michigan--Sports.
Genre Terms:
Sound recordings.
- Cassette tapes of oral history interviews
  - Abraham, Morris (football, 1948-1949) (Box 1)
    - February 1969 (Box 1)
      (tape no. 1)
    - March 23, 1971 (Box 1)
      (tape no. 2)
  - Burnley, Ken (track, 1961-1964), October 26, 1970 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 3)
  - Cephos, Richard A., December 23, 1970 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 4)
  - Codwell, John E. (basketball, 1951-1954; baseball, 1951), December 14, 1970 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 5)
  - Coleman, Horace (football, 1945; track, 1946), December 19, 1970 (includes duplicate) (Box 1)
    (tape no. 6)
  - Cooley, Keith (gymnastics, 1966), August 27, 1970 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 7)
  - Curtis, Guy (football, 1959-1961; wrestling, 1958, 1960, 1962), September 19, 1970 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 8)
  - Dickerson, Marshall (track, 1958-1961), November 28, 1970 (Box 1)
    (tape no.9)
  - Farris, Lovell (basketball, 1957-1960), December 23, 1970 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 10)
  - Fonville, Charles (track, 1944; 1946-1948), September 18, 1970 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 11)
  - Ford, Rodney (basketball, 1968-1971), April 24, 1972 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 12)
  - Goss, Tom (football, 1966-1968), May 3, 1974 with C.D. Henry; May 8, 1974 and Dave Voight, NASSH (Box 1)
    (tape no. 13)
  - Graham, Henry (tennis, 1928), September 26, 1970 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 14)
  - Hayden, Joseph, (track, 1948), December 19, 1970 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 15)
  - Hubbard, W. DeHart (track, 1923-1925), September 26, 1970 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 16)
  - Johnson, Ronald A. (football, 1966-1968), March 24, 1971 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 17)
  - Johnson, Tom (football, 1949-1951; track, 1949, 1950, 1952), September 19, 1970 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 18)
  - Kean, Daniel (tennis, 1934)
    - December 18, 1970 (Box 1)
      (tape no. 19)
    - December 18, 1971 (Box 1)
      (tape no. 20)
  - Maxey, Ken (basketball, 1966-1969), March 25, 1971 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 21)
  - Murray, Godfrey, March 24, 1971 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 22)
  - Perry, Lowell (football, 1950-1952; track, 1950, 1952), September 18, 1970 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 23)
  - Rawls, Jesse (wrestling, 1969-1970), March 24, 1971 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 24)
  - White, G. Anderson (diving, 1953-1955), December 14, 1970 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 25)
  - Ward, Willis, (football, 1932-1934; track, 1933-1935), September 19, 1970 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 27)
  - Willie, Mike (football 1963-1964, 1966 did not earn varsity letter), April 24, 1972 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 26)
  - Witherspoon, Julian W (track, 1944-1945), November 28, 1970 (Box 1)
    (tape no. 29)
  - Proposal for oral interview project (Box 1)